ARİF KÜRŞAD KAVAS

MSc, Senior Software Engineer

CAREER SUMMARY

Being working in various areas of IT environment over 15 years as a software engineer, I have gained expertise both in technical areas as well as in soft skills. Pursuing my career, I have participated in various international projects and had the chance to work in multinational teams. I am flexible and able to adapt changes, take ownership and decisive. I consider myself a continuous learner, keeping up the pace with evolving technologies.. I am a polyglot and proficient in programming languages C, C++, Java, C#, PHP on backend and Angular2+ Framework and ReactJs libraries on frontend application development.

EXPERIENCES

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (December 2018-)

Sunhill Technologies / Volkswagen Financial Services Nürnberg/Germany

- Mainly working on development of an integration portal, for Dropwizard based microservice architecture, bearing technical ownership of the product.
- Intensive front-end development using Angular Framework(with Typescript, Scss). Utilizing Java for backend development. Managing Keycloak, which is used for identity management with federations.
- Contributing to DevOps operations, fine tunings for optimized builds, experience with Ansible, Docker.
- https://paybyphone-parken.de
- Besides my work, I am also working on my side project where I utilize different libraries and technologies. On frontend I use ReactJs, NodeJs, NextJs(For SSR), Scss, Redux(For State management), Redux-Saga(For async operations within Redux). For backend I am using Phalcon PHP and PostgreSQL. I utilize Nginx to serve my web app and do all devops operations on my own.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (January 2018-November 2018)

Jotform Inc.
Izmir/Turkey

- Full stack software engineer role.
- Extensive hands on experience using Javascript, React JS, Redux for frontend development. Utilization of PHP and MySQL on backend with a distributed infrastructure on Google Cloud.
- Experience using SocketIO, REDIS, NodeJS Runtime to bring various solutions on web applications.
- www.jotform.com

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (June2014-December 2017)

ARKAS Holding S.A Izmir/Turkey

• A Full stack engineer role.

• Design and development of web/mobile applications using Javascript, AngularJS, ReactJS on

frontend and .NET on backend.

 Hands on experience on React, Redux, NodeJs, Express, Mongodb/MySQL/OracleDB, RabbitMQ, Microservices, RESTful Services, REDIS. Exposure to containers using Docker. Using .Net/C# for

back end development. Usage of MS Visual Studio, VS Code, npm, git.

• Working on embedded platforms as a side project using expertise gained in previous

experiences, using C,C++, shell scripting, gdb,ddd.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (July 2009-June 2014)

NOKIA NETWORKS
Istanbul/Turkey -Maidenhead/United Kingdom

• Developed software for GSM network backbone. Multiprocess, multithreaded scalable applications realized on Linux servers with strict performance considerations. Extensive usage of C/C++, for development of mediation framework with concentration on High Available File

Systems, Scalability, synchronization, network programming. Used Vi and Eclipse for

development and ddd/gdb for debugging, Valgrind for memory tests.

· Worked on devops pipeline of the software projects. Writing and maintaining tools for

continuous integration.

• Prepared high and low level design documentation.

• Requirement negotiation meetings on customer sites(Attended these meetings as project

technical lead for projects in Vodafone Qatar and Vodafone United Kingdom)

• Performing proof of concept meetings.

• Taking full ownership of the project throughout project lifecycle

Technologies Encountered:

Languages: C, C++, Java, PHP, HTML(For administration dashboards)

Web Servers: Apache, Tomcat, JBoss

OS: Centos/RedHAT, Solaris

Tools: Eclipse, Idea, VI editor, ddd/gdb debugger

Achievements:

Vodafone UK USSD Mediation Project:

Design and implementation of USSD mediation system for Vodafone U.K. Major responsibilities included, preparing design documentation (LLD, HLD) for the solution, designing the software architecture, hands on contribution to development of the solution. Leading software development team for development activities. Attended customer meetings in Britain with Vodafone UK and made proof of concept presentations to customer.

VF Qatar Prepaid Reporting Project:

This project was implementation of Surepay mediation solution for prepaid services in Vodafone Qatar network. Responsibilities included, attending customer workshops on customer site, during the design phase of the overall system, getting involved in requirement analysis with third parties. Writing the design documents (HLD,,LLD). Hands on involvement in development.

M1 Singapore Mailbox Migration:

Design and implementation of mailbox migration product for M1 GSM operator in Singapore. Responsible for analysis of customer needs and preparation of design documentation. Leading team of developers and managing the team for on time delivery. Hands on involvement in development of the migration tool

EMBEDDED SOFTWARE ENGINEER(October 2007 - July 2009)

GRUNDIG ELECTRONICS İzmir/Turkey

Worked as an software engineer in variety of platforms starting from ARM based processor, embedded Linux platforms and PC software. Developed LCD TV and Set Top Box software using C, C++. Working with real time operating systems. Hands on experience on embedded LINUX platforms. Development of GUI based desktop applications for automation and production, using WIN API. Experience on gdb, ddd, MS Visual Studio.

EMBEDDED SOFTWARE ENGINEER (May 2004 – December 2006)

GRF TELECOM İstanbul/Turkey

Design of analog and digital communication circuits. Gained expertise on analog and digital modulation schemes and developed a GMSK MODEM using a demodulator with one bit differential coherent detection. Used MATLAB for simulating the modulator and the demodulator, end to end testing and validation for AWGN, multipath fading, co-channel interference. Realized the system on TI's 5509 DSP. Embedded coding experience on 8051, ARM, DSP in assembly and C. Expertise on board level protocols I2C, uwire, UART.

KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

Experience in web and mobile scalable software development

Experience using Angular2+, ReactJs building responsive web apps.

Hands on skills on multi-threaded, multi process application development using C/C++

Experience on Linux System Administration, shell scripting, build tools.

Experience with Jira, HP Quality Center, CVS, GIT, TFS

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

ISTANBUL TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY

2003-2006

MSc / Electronics Engineering GPA: 3,30 / 4.0

Thesis: Design and Realization of GMSK Modem on Digital Signal Processor, Utilizing 'One Bit Differential Detection'

YEDITEPE UNIVERSITY 1999-2003

BSc/Electrical and Electronics Engineering GPA: 3,50 / 4.0

(FULL SCHOLARSHIP UPON RANK IN University Entrance Exams)

Graduated with Honours ranking 2nd in the class

BORNOVA ANADOLU LİSESİ

1995-1999

High School Education (Math-Science) GPA 4.44/5

HONOURS and **AWARDS**

%100 scholarship in university upon rank in University Entrance Exam

Graduated from university with best second GPA ranking 2nd.

Global team player award in Alcatel-Lucent upon participation and earning of AT&T Adapter Project.

TRAININGS & CERTIFICATIONS

Project Management Training (3 days) FABE

Project Management Overview Alcatel-Lucent University

Risk Management Planning Alcatel-Lucent University

Project Quality Planning Alcatel-Lucent University

Quality Assurance and Quality Control Alcatel-Lucent University

Estimating and Budgeting Project Costs Alcatel-Lucent University

The Art of Knowledge Management Alcatel-Lucent University

Solution Architect role and responsibilities Alcatel-Lucent University

Managing Projects within Organizations Alcatel-Lucent University

Operating Systems Training(2 days) Prof. Dr. Semih Bilgen METU

C Programming Language(160 Hours) C & System Programmers Association

Oracle Database 11g: Program with PL/SQL and Advanced PLSQL (5 days)Sun Educational Services Course

SQL Tuning Workshop(2 days) Sun Educational Services Course

Shell Programming for System Administrators(4 days)Sun Educational Services Course

Red Hat Certified System Administrator(5 days) **GRADE:300/300**